

SKILLS

Python	5+ yrs
NLP	5+ yrs
PyTorch	5+ yrs
Tensorflow	5+ yrs
LSTM	5+ yrs
Transformers	3+ yrs
CNN	3+ yrs
Research	3+ yrs

CONTACT

- City Square Residences, Singapore
- +64 8313 5331
- in abhishekpradhan1991
- abhishek.pradhan2008@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Sept 2009 - June 2013

Bachelor of Technology

Electronics & Telecommunication

International Institute of Information Technology, Bhubaneswar, India

ABHISHEK PRADHAN

Natural Langauge Processing | Deep Learning

PROFILE

Experience in software development.

Research and Development (R&D) experience in Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Deep Learning

Strong background in text classification, language modelling and sequence tagging (e.g. Named Entity Recognition)

Implementation experience of deep learning architectures (e.g. CNN, LSTM) using Tensorflow, Keras and PyTorch.

Enjoy reading research papers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Director, Al Research and Development Taiger Singapore Pte. Ltd., Singapore June 2020 - Present

- Responsible for leading the global Applied R&D team at Taiger.
- Responsible for working closely with the product team in providing the technical research support and development of various Natural Language Processing (NLP), Computer Vision and Deep Learning algorithms

Research Head (NLP & Deep Learning)

Taiger Singapore Pte. Ltd., Singapore

Sep 2019 - May 2020

- Responsible for leading Applied R&D team for NLP and Deep Learning at Taiger.
- Responsible for working closely with the product team in providing the technical research support and development of various Natural Language Processing (NLP) and Deep Learning algorithms
- Responsible for designing and translating the algorithms into potential applications
- Designed & implemented Question Answering System including machine reading comprehension and document ranking system .

Natural Language Processing Engineer (R&D)

Taiger Singapore Pte. Ltd., Singapore

Jan 2018 – Sep 2019

Aug 2020 - Present

Master of Science

Computer Science (Machine Learning)

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia, USA

CERTIFICATIONS

Stanford Natural Language Processing with Deep Learning (XCS224N)

Stanford University November 2019

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Coursera October 2017

PUBLICATIONS

Knowledge Graph Generation with Deep Active Learning

Abhishek Pradhan, Ketan Kumar Todi, Anbarasan Selvarasu, Atish Sanyal

International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN), 2020

Published Date Extraction System: A semi supervised approach of extraction

Nitin Kumar, Abhishek Pradhan International Journal of Engineering Trends and Technology, 2017, Vol. 45 Number 2

Personalized Terms Derivative

Nitin Kumar, Abhishek Pradhan International Conference on Information Technology, 2016

LANGUAGES

English	Full Professional	
Hindi	Native	
Odia	Native	

- Responsible for design and development of NLP technologies in Taiger's products
- Designed and implemented Resume Parsing tool using State-of-Art NLP techniques.
- Designed & built End-to-End System for Information Extraction System.
- Designed & implemented NLU system for Chatbot using Deep Learning
- Implemented and trained Named Entity Recognition for identifying Degree, Educational Institutions, Designations and Organizations for resume parsing.
 - Paper: Named Entity Recognition with Bidirectional LSTM-CNNs
 - Link: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1511.08308.pdf
- Implemented question topic classification for a chatbot with less amount of data.
 - Paper: Universal Language Model Fine-tuning for Text Classification
 - Link: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1801.06146.pdf

Research Engineer (NLP)

Rolls-Royce@NTU Corporate Lab, Singapore

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

- Designed & implemented information extraction tool for emails and attachments.
- Implemented email subject classification using 2 Layer bidirectional LSTM architecture.
- Worked on sequence tagging with short sentences using bidirectional LSTM.
- Worked in information extraction from pdf documents and word documents.
- Designed and implemented Apache Solr based Search Engine for document searching.

Software Developer (NLP)

BigInfo Labs Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore, India

Apr 2015 - Dec 2016

- Designed and Implemented NER, Published Date, Text extraction from PDF and Important keyword extraction using TextRank algorithm.
- Worked on Apache Spark and Apache Solr for indexing and parallel processing of NLP based algorithms.
- Worked on implementing Algorithms and feature development for IP based Solution.

Senior Software Engineer

Capgemini Private Limited, Bangalore, India

June 2013 - Mar 2015

- Associated with setting up of MongoDB.
- Responsible for importing JSON data to MongoDB.
- Associated with transforming imported data using Aggregation Framework.